♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ next Sunday A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ he worked
at gizmonic institute ♪
♪ just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ he did a good job cleaning up
the place ♪
♪ but his bosses didn't like him
so they shot him into space ♪
[Steam hissing]
♪ We'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ the worst we can find ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ he'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ and we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ now, keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ to make his robot friends ♪
♪ robot roll call ♪
- Cambot.
- Pan left.
- Gypsy.
- Hi, girls!
- Tom Servo.
- What a cool guy.
- Croooow!
- Wisecracker.
♪ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes ♪
♪ and other science facts ♪
♪ la-la-la ♪
♪ then repeat to yourself ♪
♪ it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ for "mystery science
theater 3000" ♪♪
[Thud, creaking]
[Zoom]
[Thud]
[Clank]
[Thudding]
Wow, Tommy,
it looks all thick.
Can we eat it now?
Patience, crow.
Proper aging is essential.
Hi, everybody, welcome
to the satellite of love.
What's that smell?
Well, Joel, we started out
making a little snack
for today's movie.
Sounds like a good idea.
What is that?
Fromage, bon ami!
You know, cheese.
I was just trying to expand
the realm of snacking
when I realized just how vital
cheese is to a sound economy.
And from now on, you're
going to see actual cheese
made right here
on the premises.
Here's the whey!
Thanks, gypsy!
Thanks, girl!
It's not like
our other projects,
like when we were
raising veal.
Ugh.
Cheese is less sensitive
to a volatile market.
We're in on the beginning
of a big microcheesery boom!
Wow, let's check it out!
Mmm! Num, num, num, num.
Ahh! Whoo hoo!
- Whoa.
- Yes!
Looks good!
Of course it's good.
America is leading on cheese.
What?
America is leading on cheese!
Right.
Now understand, Joel,
this is just the mixing tank.
Now, over here is where
the starter is added,
and then, of course, it gets
pumped into the curding tank.
That smell you're experiencing
is the enzymes,
the active
cultures in cheese.
Oh, this is just great,
you guys.
You know,
these sneakers are ruined.
I'm gonna have
to throw 'em out.
Jeez, Joel, you sound really...
Cheesed.
- Cheesed!
- [Laughter]
- Hey.
- Huh?
Don't even start with me.
[Spraying]
Agh agh!
Uh, Joel, the kids in the hole
are calling.
Take a breath.
Frank.
Well, bezoar,
let's not waste any time.
You'll remember,
we agreed to a theme
for this week's invention
exchange, and that theme was...
[All]
Action figures?
No, it was action figures.
Tell you what, we'll make it
a competition.
You win, and we'll
all enjoy local hero.
You lose, and you'll be forced
to watch a film stinkier
than your little Pearl's cheese
factory, "monster a-go go."
And frank here can act
as our impartial judge, 'Kay?
You have got
to be kidding me!
We're gonna get burned,
Joel.
We're gonna
get roasted like nuts.
Oh, come on,
you guys.
Frank's a square fella.
Besides, I think
it'll be fun.
Shall we toss a coin,
see who goes first?
I did, we won.
[Laughs]
Let him have it, Steve.
- Whoo!
- You know it, frank.
All action figures have
two things in common:
Merchandising and accessories.
But there is a fatal flaw in
this philosophy that yours truly
and the monkey here have rooted
up like the pussy scab it is.
The component factor.
Most kids can't be satisfied
with just a simple startup kit,
one doll, naked,
alone and afraid.
You gotta have
all the accessories.
But why stop with the doll?
Don't you see?
You sell a component doll.
Introducing Johnny longtorso,
the doll who is himself,
sold separately.
♪♪ [Blows harmonica]
♪ Johnny longtorso ♪
♪ the man who comes in pieces ♪
[Imitate whip cracking]
♪ He's long ♪
Now, you might want to start
with the longtorso starter unit
and then add the action head.
Just look at the detail
on this.
Then accentuate the head
with the right and left eyeball
action packs, plus, Johnny's
perfect ears, sold separately.
Now get your hero up off
the floor and give him something
to do with the left arm,
right arm,
right leg,
left leg limb packs.
Then, if you order now, you also
get the high performance
right and left foot upgrades.
All for only $10
with this coupon.
Not included.
And then gear up for high
adventure with the hair kit,
the rugged nose option,
the sleek and sassy
butt portions,
the realistic action batch,
and so much more!
Now, altogether,
this hunk of rubber would go
for about eight bucks,
but sold separately,
one Johnny longtorso unit
can bring in $300.
It all adds up to merchandising
profit, the American way.
Well, schmo?
Evil!
You are evil!
- Evil!
- Calm--
calm down, honey,
it's okay, come on.
Let's show 'em what we got.
- Come on, sirs.
- Yeah, come on!
I decided that this week,
my bots have what it takes
to take you on
in the invention exchange.
Yeah!
And they've come up
with a decidedly UN-evil line
of affordable nonviolent
action figures.
Yeah!
Come on, let's show 'em
what we got, guys.
- Yeah!
- All right, Joel.
Well, my figure
is called action Oxford.
It's Edward de vere,
the 17th Earl of Oxford,
well-placed in the court
of Elizabeth and revered
by the crowned heads
of Europe.
Why, it's been well-argued
that action Oxford
was the real author of
Shakespeare's plays and sonnets.
Wow, cool.
Show 'em all the features.
Well, he writes, and he's got
a great fencing arm.
Oh, and he embodies
that enigmatic sadness
that was prevalent
among late renaissance
intellectuals and courtesans,
and he costs only 12 bucks,
complete.
Wow, educational,
fun, and historically accurate.
- Good job, Tom.
- Yeah!
Okay, crow, who's
this cool guy over here?
Oh, he's just the host organism,
but, hey, look in his mouth.
- Oh?
- [Chuckles] Yeah.
Introducing
woodscrew tapeworm!
Yuck!
He lives out his life cycle
in the entrails
of the host body
until he's expelled or dies.
Cool, a parasite!
Just look at the detail.
Yeah, the digestive tract's as
exciting as the Amazon jungle.
There's danger, adventure,
and half-digested food
around every curve.
Wow, I want to play
with this one right now.
Okay, gypsy,
it's your turn.
Take us over the top.
What you got?
Yeah, well, it's world champion
track sensation Wilma Rudolph.
Ooh.
She does the 400 meter hurdles
in under 115,
and she's a great
role model to boot.
- Cool.
- Wow.
Now that's cool
and inspiring.
Beat that, you sirs.
Come on!
- Yeah!
- Beat Wilma Rudolph, come on!
- Frank?
- We won.
You lose.
I'm going
to spit on you now,
just a little spittle called
"monster a-go go."
"Monster a-go go," Joel.
And because I'm gloating,
I'm going to stick you
with a short as well.
It's flaming little sack
of dog poopy called...
[Chuckling]
"Circus"...
[Laughing]
"On ice."
[Cackling evilly]
[All]
"Circus on ice"?
[Buzzer, all scream]
♪♪
Ohh.
Ahh.
Hey, you got your circus
on my ice.
You got your ice on my circus.
Two bad things
that go worse together.
♪♪
Um, I'd like
a sloe gin circus.
I'd like my circus
straight up.
Now you can have both.
What, is this a Max fleischer
cartoon?
Oh, it looks that way.
"Sparling and darling."
"Based on the actual case files
of the Toronto skating club."
Well, gee, I seen him
in my nightmares.
Step right up for the newest
thing in show business.
Karaoke!
See the circus on ice.
Today's glittering
ice carnivals
have come a long way from
the annual masquerades...
Oh, they have?
That once wound up Toronto's
skating season.
Yet still today, they are
the results of months
of practice as typists
and housewives...
Hey, Bella abzug.
... glide from
their workaday world
into the make-believe wonderland
of the theater.
But they are soon returned
to their lives
of quiet desperation.
Every branch of show business
is their inspiration...
Whoo!
From the brassy
excitement of the circus.
Yes!
And no circus is complete
without pink candy floss.
♪ These two girls ♪
♪ they make quite the pair ♪
♪ they both come from
your worst nightmare ♪
♪ they will haunt your soul
forever ♪
♪ and now when you see pink ♪
♪ you're gonna think ♪
♪ we're doomed ♪
♪ they are agents of Satan ♪
[Laughing]
Stop it, Tom.
Candy on ice.
That's nice.
Oh, mama, you make it
sound so good.
But here comes a herd
of performing zebras.
There's probably nothing quite
like them this side of Africa.
Each one
has been trained to...
[All]
Ew!
... precise teamwork
at the crack
of their driver's whip.
We're getting into a whole
weird area here.
Yes, it's "sexist
male fantasies on ice."
[All laughing]
♪♪ [Quacking along with music]
You know, this is about when
Donnie and Marie come out.
- Yep.
- Oh.
I am not a zebra!
♪♪
[Quacking to the beat]
And now, the little bareback
rider exults in her victory
over the wild beasts.
Uh-huh...
And, incidentally,
shows olympic skating form
as she does so.
Ooh.
I can do that!
Well, she can do this
'cause she feels fresh.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh.
[Quacking to the beat]
This way to the kill floor.
In their galloping finale,
the spritely creatures show
their pride in being the only
troop of trained zebras on ice.
Yes, it's dehumanized
objectified circus on ice.
The view changes as Jacqueline
du bief takes the spotlight.
Jacqueline?
One of the world's
great figure skaters,
the girl from Paris
tells the story
of a Fawn's fight for life.
What was she doing?
The Fawn plays happily in
the dim forest without a care.
Prelude to the afternoon
of a murder.
♪♪
You know, you guys,
there's nothing sadder
than a gut-shot Fawn...
- Hmm.
On ice.
Especially.
Please, she's an artist,
do not throw pennies at her.
Suddenly, hunters approach.
Frantically, the Fawn
tries to escape.
Suddenly, she darts
across the highway.
[Screeching]
[Imitates gunshot]
At last,
the hunters close in.
There is no escape.
Unshaven, stinky and boozed-up
on rumple minze,
the hunters spray
bullets into the woods.
Oh, mom, I don't want to--
I don't like
the circus on ice anymore.
I want to go home!
Shut up and watch the deer
get slaughtered, it's fun.
Viscera is trailing
from her stomach.
The meat will not be good.
Venison!
- Venison!
- Okay.
[Both]
Venison! Ven...
- ... ison.
- They shoot.
- They score!
- The bullet finds its Mark.
Aw, she skates over her own
intestines.
Ms. Du bief illustrates
the exquisite blend
of brilliant skating
and interpretive dancing,
which won her
the world's championship
as she plays out the last
moments of the dying Fawn.
And now a clown
will deliver her eulogy.
There's always a spot
in a skating carnival
for the little fellows.
But not in this show.
... brave army of toy soldiers
is called out
to deal with
the only dragon in captivity.
Operation desert ice storm.
♪♪
The soldiers destroy
the delicate balance of nature.
A volley of shots gravely fired
disintegrates the menace.
Gravely?
That thing was grazing.
Yeah, kill, heh.
And now, the spotlight falls on
a world of delicate loveliness.
- And kills them.
- The ballet.
Spinning the substance
that dreams are made of,
the beautiful ballerinas
of the ice
create a world
of fairy make believe.
Yeah, as long as you drop before
you came in the shower.
Ballet skating is
a comparatively new development
of the art.
It requires all the grace
and control of the dancer
combined with the rhythmic sweep
of the skater.
The Emmett Kelly girls do
their famous spotlight routine.
♪♪
Vomit sprays out in a beautiful
technicolor dream.
You know, we should
have worn our raincoats.
Oh, yes.
They would bring--
[coughing]
The girls with the bruised legs
have to wear the long dresses.
This little number
is named,
"always a bridesmaid,
never a bride."
Individual artistry is blended
into brilliant choreography.
On Broadway, but not here.
... etches its delicate patterns
on the glassy stage
to interpret
a moonlight concerto on ice.
With a filbert nut.
- Every circus has its acrobats.
- Except this one.
There's a thrill a second
in their breathtaking routines,
and when it's
all done on skates,
these daring young performers
are accomplishing feats
even more difficult than many
an aerialist in a real circus.
You know, even my mom
would be bored at this.
♪ Torn between two skaters ♪
♪ fee--♪
oh!
Yes, it's "Jules and Jim"
on ice.
As they perform
their death-defying spin,
the girls' heads barely
miss the ice.
Women are pulled apart
like fresh bread.
♪♪
It all adds up
to split-second artistry.
At the civic center,
but not here.
... the fiber of an athlete,
the precision of an juggler,
and the nerve
of a test pilot.
And the boredom
of an accordionist.
Today's great skating carnivals
are as sophisticated as bop,
as spectacular
as the boudoir boogie.
And as dull as a beige room.
This is like
watching paint dry.
Oh, it's easy when you
sit down.
♪♪
Heh heh, girls.
See if you can spot the men
in this chorus line.
[Chuckling lecherously]
Look, she's got
a sheep's butt.
Ah.
[Scatting]
Suddenly,
mitosis takes place.
The DNA strand separates
in a dazzling display of color.
Hi, prophase!
Hi, anaphase!
I'm putting a stop to this.
This is the age
of style in skating,
of form as well
as acrobatic.
Too bad it isn't the age
of talent.
[Chuckles]
Wow, really swingin', man.
Hey, she's got a saggy diaper
that leaks.
- Hope not.
- Yeah.
♪♪
Can you imagine
if you were the kind of person
who enjoyed this?
The syncopated rhythm
of the dance...
... is not working tonight.
New style, on skates.
The practiced precision
of the pony chorus
brings new excitement
on steel.
Yeah, taste my steel.
Uck.
All the color and pageantry
of a stage revue...
... is missing.
And brought from behind
the footlights into
the spotlights of the modern
skating carnival.
The only consolation
is that they're all dead now!
... for men and women
from every walk of life
who come together
each year
for the fun of building a newer
and more dazzling spectacle.
Oh, right, that's fun.
As the flashing blades
twirl to a dizzy climax,
the skaters bring to an end
no ordinary circus,
but truly a circus on ice.
By federico fellini.
We say good-bye to the vibrating
circus train.
[Gurgling]
Ah.
♪♪
Hey, I know this.
[Humming theme
to "Hawaii five-o"]
No, no, that's not it here.
- Oh, I know.
- Wipeout!
[Humming "wipe out"]
No, no, I don't--
Elvis has staggered
out of the building.
It's Billy pilgrim.
Oh, that's a new L.A. club.
Ohh...
"Monster a-go go"?
I thought this was gonna be
"munster, go home."
- Ohh.
- You know what, guys?
I have a feeling this is gonna
be a tough one.
No, it might
not be too bad.
No, I think Joel's right.
This one has stinkburger
written all over it.
- Yes.
- [Sighs]
Now, come on, you can't tell
just from the credits.
No, no,
it's a feeling I have.
My gut instincts tell me this
is gonna hurt real bad.
Joel, it's not healthy
to have such a negative attitude
right out of the gate.
It's just common sense,
crow.
There's a feeling
of incompetence
already in the air here.
You know, we might as well
face up to it.
Well, I refuse
to give in so soon.
I'm gonna riff away
like it's nobody's business.
I can't think of anything now,
but...
[Chuckles]
Well.
"The other 'thuh'"?
"Thh." the other "thh."
- "Thh."
- "thh."
♪♪
Jeff Smith,
the frugal screenwriter!
Now, don't write in,
for heaven's sake.
♪♪
Hey, didn't
Sheldon Seymour write
"the other side of midnight"?
Uh... hmm.
Hey, what a coincidence.
There are two guys
named bill rebane.
Heh, you know, 'cause you
see with the--
and the guys, they're--
this is gonna suck.
What you're about to see
may not even be possible
within the narrow limits
of human understanding.
So let's forget it
right now.
A space capsule is rocketed
into orbit on schedule.
[Humming "ride of
the valkyries"]
Its mission, to observe
new objects circling the earth,
satellites which no nation
has launched.
As the capsule
reached its orbit,
communications with it
suddenly went silent.
Several days passed.
A search team headed
by colonel Steve Connors...
[All]
Hi, Steve!
... an intensive search
of the entire area.
This is Connors.
Go ahead, patrol two.
Go ahead,
pump three.
Nothing in sight
except trees.
Coming in, over.
Um, I'll need extra Jack sauce
and some ketchup.
Over and out.
In a wooded area not far
from the space agency
astrophysical laboratories
in Chicago,
observers reported
that a strange object
had fallen to earth.
A coke bottle.
Patrol two to Connors.
Come in, over.
Okay, now you see that thing?
You push it down, all the way
down to the floor there.
This is Connors.
Come in, patrol two.
Nag, nag, nag.
I just spotted something.
Looks like it
might be our stray man.
I'm going down there
to take a look.
Hey, good lookin', we'll be back
to pick you up later.
They may have
found something.
Was it the space capsule?
You have five seconds
to answer.
Ding! Ding!
Ding!
[Imitating buzzer]
I'm sorry,
the answer was no.
Traffic is heavy
on the outbound 94.
You might want to take
an alternate route.
How does it look, Jim?
This is so cool.
Hey, wait a minute.
That's right, this is it.
Take the kazoo
out of your mouth.
Yeah, that's it all right.
Looks pretty battered
from here.
I'm setting it down.
Good-bye, Steve!
[All humming "m a s h" theme]
I like it.
It's nice
they shot this film
at such a pretty time
of the year, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Ha.
Well, I guess this means
the helicopter's landing.
Yep.
- Aah.
- Here it goes.
Landing.
I didn't know
what to say, Steve.
I didn't know you felt
this way.
Oh.
Wait a minute.
There's an alien inside.
They're talking
to Charlie brown's mom.
Oh, my god!
[Groaning]
He chucked, Steve.
This is captain Connors
calling patrol two.
Connors calling patrol two.
He's not home right now,
can I take a message?
Jim, do you read me?
Come in,
patrol two.
Wayne, pick up,
I know you're there.
What happened?
It sounded like
he was in trouble.
No duh.
We better take a look.
Hmm.
Uh, take a left
by that bush.
So the government
drives stock chevys?
I think it's a biscayne.
Ooh. Ooh.
Oh, yeah, this is when
NASA was just a car
and a helicopter, right?
Mm-hmm, yeah.
Storefront in a strip mall.
Yeah,
and a vacant lot.
Okay, now, cut that out!
Without question,
this was the capsule
that had put Douglas
into orbit.
- Right.
- [Laughing]
And, without question, Douglas
was gone without a trace.
Douglas was pear-shaped, very
short, and stood the whole way.
[Giggling]
Well, ray, look, it's filled
with schlitz cans.
Oh, for crying out loud...
Well, thank goodness les Paul
is backing them up on guitar.
♪♪
Earl, it's not
your break yet.
The helicopter pilot,
who had discovered the capsule,
was dead, horribly
mangled in a way
no one had ever seen before.
Oh, quit playing
with his face, Aaron.
[Doorbell rings]
Meanwhile, in a soap opera
not far away...
What do you want?
Well, Laura, how are you?
How's Jimmy?
Oh, he's fine, I just sent him
over to Mrs. Williams.
- Hi, honey.
- Air kiss.
Have some coffee?
No, no thanks.
Tom?
Yes, please.
Make it good this time!
Huh, she usually keeps a bunch
of m&ms in that bowl.
Hmm.
Oh, feel free to stink
the house up.
Jeez.
Well, here's
the witch's brew.
I mean, coffee, coffee.
♪ Times like these were made
for taster's choice ♪
It's about frank,
isn't it?
[Imitating spit take]
Ruth, the capsule came back.
This coffee's warmer
than frank is.
What about frank?
I don't know.
He had all the emergency
equipment he needed, but...
He was just stupid.
Ohh.
Oh, what is it all about?
- Alfie.
- The shot was a success.
The capsule
did come back.
But frank didn't.
It's just that
we don't know whether
the radiation repellent
worked or not.
Oh, I know I shouldn't
feel this way.
It's his life,
but... well...
Ever since Harry died, frank's
been like a father to Jimmy.
Harry?
Wait, wait, slow down.
Try not to even think about it
right now.
What am I going
to tell Jimmy?
Who's Jimmy?
Would you like me
to spend the night?
Oh, you'd like that,
wouldn't you?
I've got to get back
to the lab room.
I don't want to spend
any more time on this
than I already have.
- If there's anything I can do.
- Thank you, Carl.
Course, we'll be cutting off
the pension,
- you understand.
- Mm-hmm.
Hi, Dr. Carl.
- Hiya, space cadet.
- Frank's dead!
Jimmy, I thought you were over
at Mrs. Williams.
I had to get
some more rocket parts.
Poor kid.
When's uncle frank
coming home?
You'll have to make do
with uncle Bob and uncle Jim
and uncle Phil and uncle Roy
and uncle Tim and...
Remember he went
on a long trip?
Burned on reentry, huh?
He promised
to take me fishing.
Well, some trips are longer
than we expected.
Make other plans,
Jimmy.
What's wrong with mommy?
Mommy's not feeling
very well.
Suppose you go upstairs,
and when we're all through,
we'll have a nice big
ice cream soda, huh?
Yeah, that solves everything.
Hey, Timmy,
my dad's dead again!
Can I come over for dinner?
No, no, I can't take anymore.
Oh, look, let's not make
a bigger deal out of this
than it really is.
[Phone rings]
[All] Aah!
Whew.
Jeez.
Got that?
Face like spinach dip?
Horribly mangled?
No dental records?
Hmm, too bad.
All right, now.
I'll be right over.
Well, looks like he died
in a state of sin.
- Oh, sorry.
- They've located the cabin.
- Two words, "closed casket."
- Is it frank?
I'll let you know
as soon as I find out.
Wait, Carl,
I want to go with you.
Honey, he'll call if there
is any news.
No, I want to be with you.
[Sighs and hums]
So sad.
♪ Hum de-Dee hee hee,
hoo-ah hoo-ah ♪
♪ hum de-Dee hee hee ♪
♪ hoo-ah hoo-ah ♪
♪ hum-- ♪
- Hi!
- Hi.
♪ Di Dee hee hee,
hoo-ah hoo-ah ♪
Um... uh...
Uh...
Oh. Hmm.
Crow?
Yes?
I don't get you.
Oh.
- Are you mad?
No! No.
Good!
Because I want to like you,
but I just don't understand
where you're coming from.
Sure, uh...
What's not to get,
though, gypsy?
I just am, I hang out.
Oh, oh, I know.
It's just that, well, you know,
I don't really get you.
Yeah, okay.
Uh, maybe I can help.
Uh, to start with,
I'm a robot.
I use
cyber-based bubble memory.
Is that what's
confusing you?
N-No.
Is it that I work off unix
and can use
a variety
of operating systems?
Well, I guess that's a start.
Well... I've undergone
a complex personal evolution
wherein painful confusion
has given way
to what I like to think of
as some degree of wisdom
culminating in my current
zarathustrian sense of self.
- Is that it?
- No.
If that helps you,
it's good, but...
Gypsy, I don't know what--
is it that I often panic
while making sandwiches?
Yeah!
Well...
Well, maybe it's that kind
of thing.
Is it that I smell conspiracy
in everything
and I don't know
what I mean most of the time?
Oh, that's perhaps a small piece
of the puzzle, but I...
Gypsy...
Is it an odor?
No. Well...
No.
Well, maybe it's Tom
I don't get.
Oh, brother.
Like a zippo lighter without
any flint, I can't believe...
[Humming]
Ugh.
- Tom?
- Yo.
I don't get you.
Nobody does.
I'm the wind, baby.
[Humming]
Hmm.
Jeez, aren't there any roads
in this town?
It's a hover bonneville.
I think this is the movie
version of "darkness visible,"
by William styron.
Wait, I want
to come with you.
No, Ruth, you stay here.
Jeez, you're high-maintenance.
♪♪
Well, um, could I have the keys
so I can listen to the radio?
- Gee.
- Yes?
Jim Taylor.
The helicopter pilot.
How did it happen?
We don't know, sir.
We were having contact with him
from the ground car.
Suddenly, he let out
a yell and then went blank.
There was nothing we could do.
You'd better take a look
at the body, Carl.
He said "garp," then he said
"good," and then he died.
I've never seen
anything like it.
He's shriveled up like
a dried prune.
Like a drag queen?
Looks like
some kind of a burn.
But it didn't touch his hair
or his clothes.
But he's horribly mutilated.
That's what's
left of him.
They shaved his moustache,
those animals!
There's something else
I want to show you.
Uh, Rick,
could I get a ride home?
What do you make of this,
Carl?
Looks like
a Meadow muffin.
They look like severe burns.
What could have
caused such burns?
Mexican food?
I don't know.
Probably some kids' prank.
Yeah, kids are always
mutilating people.
Take the body
back to the hospital.
Oh, good, now what about
the capsule?
The equipment's
on the way now.
All right, but I want you
to stay here until it arrives.
I don't want anything disturbed
until Dr. Logan has had a chance
to examine it carefully.
All right, Dr. Schreiber.
We'd better get
back to the lab.
There's nothing more
we can do here.
Robert goulet
and Martin milner--
they're cops.
What are we gonna tell Ruth?
What do you mean "we"?
Can we, Carl?
What do you mean?
There's no real proof
that Douglas is dead.
- There's no body.
- No bounce.
Maybe we shouldn't
tell her anything.
Yeah, let's toy
with her for a while.
Nobody hopes for a miracle
more than I, Henry.
The pope does.
There's no sense
grabbing at straws.
Even assuming he was
blown clear of the wreckage
before the doctors
had ran out.
You're deep, Terry.
The wreckage here is enough
to tell the story.
I'm not convinced.
The condition
of that body...
Something's not right.
We'll probably get the facts
in the laboratory.
Maybe you're right.
Hungry?
[Scoffs] Couldn't even afford
to hang the chalkboard.
Still mad, Evan?
Let's talk.
I thought you went home.
Too much on my mind.
Uh, you've got a bit
of toilet paper on your shoe.
When did you get back
to the lab?
I never went home either.
I kept thinking
about the body.
Something about the capsule
still haunts me.
But I'm trying
to find an answer.
Try to find a microphone!
Here I am.
Did you come up
with anything?
Take a look.
You know enough
about these things.
- Hmm?
- Hey, that's my wife!
It's a human tissue.
Correct.
But it's different, though.
I've never seen
anything quite like it.
I took it from
Taylor's body.
Huh?
He was literally cooked to death
in a matter of seconds.
- That sounds delicious.
- By what?
Something so charged with
radiated energy,
contact caused
instant death.
You infer the capsule came back
with radioactive energy?
The capsule
didn't kill Taylor.
Here.
Look, could we get a miracle-ear
or something?
Tiny scraps of metal...
Seems normal.
It is--
no radioactivity.
I don't like you.
Then it was something else.
Remember the scorch Mark
on the ground near the body?
Yeah, that was fun.
Whatever killed Taylor stood
while it was placed
right were the body was.
Analysis of the grass
from that spot
showed clearly the same effect
was on Taylor's body.
Henry, I know what
you're driving at but...
- Shut up.
- But it's impossible.
Douglas couldn't
have survived.
Why not?
The nose cone
of the capsule did.
- The chute opened.
- I'm aware of that.
Though we both
know that it opened
while he passed over
our radius.
Passover gradient?
Maybe if I go along with you,
I'll hear something that--
that cycles [indistinct].
That's...
A fragment boo-bad?
And why should it be
radioactive?
Washington's radioactive?
I thought it was lower
than [indistinct].
With a road apple?
I don't have any answers
to those questions yet.
But my brother and I
are working on it.
He's rather
Dr. Bellows-esque.
- Let's face facts.
- Mm-hmm.
One, a capsule comes back.
One cat in a bag?
A man is seared to death
by an unknown force.
- Five.
- Three...
No, three, sir.
We know an excessive amount
of radiation came back
with the capsule,
and four...
- I'm Percy dovetonsils.
- Douglas is missing.
But the radiation
is what bothers me.
Did you tell Dr. Manning
of this?
No, not yet.
And I'd appreciate it
if you wouldn't either.
At least until we have
some more answers.
Do I need a shave?
Well, it's entirely
up to you, Henry.
Take as much
time as you need.
Bacon as much time
as you need?
Let's pray that something else
doesn't happen.
Starting...
Now, go!
Good night.
- Ah.
- Good night.
Hmm, "dear diary, well,
you won't believe
who waltzed
back into my life today..."
You know what?
This is like "the blob."
No, no, "the thing."
No, it's "it."
Or maybe "them."
No, it's "three coins
in the fountain."
Uh, sort of... thing.
So I guess
we're through, then.
We're finally going to meet
the invisible member
- of this project.
- Yes.
Strange feeling,
working three years
with a man you've never met.
He must be talking about
his agent.
[Laughs]
Oh.
We will return to George Kennedy
in "airport '75."
Jeez, I hate having to drive
my friends to the airport, god.
Mm, ah, sorry,
I broke the ladder!
[Grunting]
Early in 1965, president Johnson
visited Saigon.
He was greeted
by general westmoreland.
The episode was considered
important enough
for the civilian head
of the project,
Dr. Chris Manning,
to make an emergency visit.
Hi, Chris.
Carl.
It isn't often we have such
a short time between visits.
How are you, Connors?
Fine,
thank you, general.
He's the sky cap,
you dope!
Dr. Chris Manning,
Dr. Schreiber, captain Connors.
- Captain.
- Hi, major.
Chris, colonel.
Colonel, Chris.
I've been looking forward
to meeting you for a long time.
The pleasure's mine, doctor.
I've been impressed
with some of your theories.
I'd like to discuss them
with you one day.
- Over cocktails.
- I'd like that.
I pulled Chris off of vacation
to come down here with me.
And his secretary.
After Logan told me
about the pilot,
I decided it was time
to break security
and bring you two together.
I would like to examine the body
as soon as possible.
We should be finished
with the report by now.
We can go to the hospital...
- His face is gone!
- Fine.
I'll fill you in on the details
on the way over.
- Oh.
- It's a drive-by shooting!
[Imitating gunshots]
So, beef 'n barrel?
That sound--
how about barnaby's?
Barnaby's, then, huh?
Barnaby's is good.
Yeah, barnaby's.
- Yep.
- That'll be good.
Hey, general,
midasize it, huh?
Rattle-rattle, clutter-clutter,
boom-boom-boom...
Weird, it gets quieter
when you close the door.
Hmm.
[Imitating bassy car stereo]
Hey.
- [Gasps]
- Why, general!
♪♪
Oh, they decided to go
to shakey's.
- Ohh.
[Laughter]
Hello, Laverne.
Hello, shirl.
♪♪
It's "the Patty Duke show."
♪ Rock rock rock rock rock
and roll high school... ♪
Oh, there's Lenny Bruce
over there.
Hmm.
Must be dancing
at the slipped disc.
A sullen Jack kerouac pulls out
a "j" in the middle of the room.
Chad, the sensitive teen.
Hey, you put your cigarette out
in my black cow!
Hmm.
So, this is what goes on
in the teacher's lounge, huh?
[Laughter]
I'll have a little of this
balsamic vinegar here.
Yeah.
Mm, mm.
Gah! Not good, really.
[Clears throat
and coughs]
I'm pretty sure this is where
the movie really takes off.
This is the "a-go go" part.
Whoa, he's got
an action torso there.
Ha-ha, I'm dancing!
What is this,
"the Lloyd thaxton show"?
Kinda.
Not him, honey.
He's got action hips.
The Alpha male
dominates the herd.
Come on back here
and fight like a girl!
Come on!
Aww.
Hmm? Hmm?
♪♪
That's a strange car alarm.
Django rinehart
tunes up his guitar.
♪ Here in my car,
I feel safest of all ♪
The thin blue line.
♪♪
[All]
♪ eee-oh ♪
Huh, well, I guess introductions
are in order, heh.
What changes the delicate
interlocking of fates
that determines
life or death?
A series of ifs.
Ands or buts.
If the girl had danced
with her boyfriend
instead of the other boy,
and they
had stayed later,
if the two of them hadn't
parked to kiss and make up...
But that
is not what happened,
and fate and history
never deal in "ifs."
I'm hearing your
internal monologue, honey.
[Dog barking]
He made her bark!
Ooh.
I have to let that dog
out of the trunk.
It's creepy the clown.
[Screaming]
♪♪
♪ eee-oh ♪
Thank goodness my allstate man
was on the scene.
Are we awfully fast,
or was that a jump cut?
He's mangled in another horrible
way I've never seen before.
- That guy's creative.
- Good god.
- Jump back, kiss myself.
- What happened to him?
From the looks of him,
general,
I'd say the same thing
that happened
to the helicopter pilot.
Could you turn down
your reverb, Chris?
- Who found him, captain?
- One of the search party.
Did you see anything?
No, doctor,
not a thing.
Ah, you two.
Hey, nice car.
Nobody wants it,
I'll take it.
Wow, look at all
the butane cans!
[Woman groaning]
General.
What was that?
Uh, general?
Stay with the tour, general.
General!
He's always--
always doing that.
Tom, Phil?
Where is everybody?
Over here, Chris!
Oh.
I am a fugitive
from a chain gang.
♪♪
♪ jingle bell, jingle bell,
jingle bell rock ♪
Jeez, productive night.
This guy's
got 30 bucks on him.
Ooh.
Did he just
crack her knuckles?
Sounded like it.
Hey, look, you can move her
contact around, it's fun.
I think she's
all right, general.
- She's in shock.
- Good.
Let's get her
right back to the lab.
Oh, yes, let's get--
- right, to the lab.
- I'll take you to the lab.
- My personal lab.
- Lab, yeah, taking her.
- Do some tests.
- Yes. [Laughs]
♪♪
She's gonna look great
in a petri dish.
Is he playing her?
No, Ravi shankar
is tuning up somewhere.
I took the grill out, I think
there's room in the trunk now.
Hey, shove
Mr. Hoffa over there.
♪♪
What is this,
Chinese music torture?
In the southern provinces,
the rice paddies are flooded
in the spring
as they have been
for thousands of years.
Stop it!
Thank you.
Boy, is it ever a white day.
It must be
the whitest day yet.
Mm-hmm.
Dr. Logan, puzzled by
the laboratory analysis...
Blew up.
... made his own exploratory
trip back to the landing area.
He's listening
to books on tape.
His theory was proved right,
and it was proved right
so unexpectedly
and so violently
that he never lived
to record it.
Poor, ridiculous sap.
Ah.
[Bird chirping]
Hmm?
Hey, he's good at that--
he should be on Carson.
You should hear him
do his crested grebe.
Really good.
Well, he brought
a bottle of t.J. Swann.
It's "Mr. Hobbs
takes a vacation."
[Bird chirping]
♪ Dog and butterfly
up in the air ♪
♪ he likes to fly,
dog and butterfly ♪
I'm never gonna find a plug-in
for my hairdryer.
Agh.
Now there's a man
outstanding in his field!
- Doh!
- Okay! Uhh.
Uh-uh.
A young ghermazian brother
scouts locations.
Now I can take my clothes off
and run around, whoo!
A lone bull human
seeks a worthy mate.
As I mentioned earlier,
there is tremendous horror
out here... somewhere.
Dawn on the serengeti.
[Imitating tribal drums
and birds squawking]
Tooki tooki!
[British accent]
How not to be seen.
Oh, well, this is where
Van gogh
painted his famous
"crows in corn."
Frozen corn?
Any moment now,
unspeakable horror.
Stay with me.
He's looking for Nolan Ryan,
so he can clock his fastball.
[Birds chirping]
Let's see, I think I know
whose woods these--
no, no, whose woods
are these anyway?
No, damn, no.
Hmm, long, skinny turd.
Two, three days old.
[Sniffing]
Fresh.
Okay, perhaps
I was mistaken.
The horror must be
in a later scene.
Now with the Wagner
power painter,
you can paint
the whole forest in a day.
Ah, well.
I guess nobody cares but me.
[Sighs]
[Soda can opening]
Hey.
You got a can of pop?
Hey, give me
some of that.
Yeah, pass it over here.
I don't have
a can of pop.
You know you're
not supposed
to bring anything
into the theater.
Well, what's that, then?
What do you got?
Give me sips.
- Come on.
- It's my medicine.
"Medicine."
come on, share.
No, um...
Designer Karl lager-field.
[Pinging]
I don't have anything.
Hey, well, just drop the ball,
take the stroke!
[Pinging continues]
Oh, so this is what happened
to Robert vesco.
- Aah!
- There!
Your announcer
feels vindicated.
This is extremely horrible.
Mo udall!
[Pinging continues]
What? What?
Well, that didn't
make me happy.
You remember that song?
What song?
Would you like to dance?
No.
Not without music,
that would be wrong.
You know, Chris, that dash of
gray is very distinguished.
Cut the crap, Lorraine.
What do you want?
Half my income?
One would think
we were getting older.
[Laughs]
Aren't we?
Heh heh.
Oh, waiter?
My date is ice cold.
Two martinis, please.
With two anchovy olives.
I'm cutting loose
tonight.
Now, how did I
happen to forget that?
That's very easy.
How many years has it been?
You mean
since we ordered?
Jeez.
Too flippin' many.
I've got
the most peculiar feeling
that something is
terribly wrong.
Oh, that's the scotch eggs.
Ever since frank
was lost.
Maybe it's nothing, call it
feminine intuition, but...
Or gas.
When Carl told me the capsule
had come back, i--
I almost expected it.
Uh, barkeep, could you
freshen my date?
And now another death.
I keep telling myself there's
nothing to fear, but i--
I can't quite
make myself believe it.
Now, you two want ham
in that omelet?
Yes, there's a phone call
for you, sir.
Oh, thank you, waiter.
Huh, invisi-waiter.
My, he's got the bladder
the size of a juice glass.
Hmm.
Ah ha, that's what she'd
like to do to him.
Stir his olive?
Yeah.
- Oh.
- [Slurps]
[Gulps and burps]
Uh, Ruth, do you know
where port wien road is?
Uh, near bourbon street?
Yes, it's a mile
from the site.
Why?
What is it, what happened?
Is that where
the bathroom is?
Maybe your intuition
was right.
Well, let's go.
Hmm!
There's been another strange
accident.
- Oh, no.
- Let's go.
♪ Bourbon street,
bourbon street ♪
- Come on, throw it to me!
- Hey, got it!
- Here it, comes, Tommy.
- Okay, here you go, bro.
- Oh, sorry, you missed.
- Hey, hey, come on.
- Throw it to me!
- Whoa!
- Oh, give it to him, Joel.
- Hey, okay, okay.
Crow, you know what?
I think Tom and I
are all done with it.
Ah, face!
Ha ha ha!
East, east, y'all.
[Laughter]
Here it comes, yeah.
I'll be your best friend,
come on!
A friend who can't catch?
- I don't think so.
- Got it.
Yeah, well, your limbs
don't even work.
Well, I happen to be
propelling the ball
with my hover skirt,
thank you very much.
Here it comes, Tommy.
Whoa!
- Alley-oop!
- Ooh!
Oh, pepper, pepper.
Okay, I don't even
want to play.
You know what?
I don't even care, I hate balls.
Play all you want,
I don't care.
- Okay, we will.
- No, I don't care.
- Ah!
- He's gonna get it!
Oh, he's got it!
[Overlapping chatter]
Oh, my-- ooh!
Ha! I got it!
- Here it comes, Tom.
- Hey!
- Here we go.
- Oh, got it.
Oh, I'm gonna get
in the theater early.
Hup, hup, hup, hup.
Hey, hup.
Hey, Tommy, go long
for the hail Mary!
- I'm going!
- Go, go, go!
I'm open, I'm open!
[Buzzer]
- We got movie sign! Ohh!
- I'm open!
- I got it, I got it.
- No, I got it, I got it.
It's coming to me,
it's coming to me.
Here it comes.
I got it, I got it.
Hey, here's a snickers
for being a good sport, man.
How about that Anita Ekberg?
I sure wouldn't
mind a--
ooh.
He looks so peaceful.
Absolutely unbelievable,
general.
You called me
away from dinner for this?
He looks worse
than the others.
He started out worse
I suppose again there wasn't
anybody around who saw anything.
- No.
- It's New York.
One of our men recognized
Logan's car
on his way
to town this morning.
The car was still there when
he came back this afternoon,
so he stopped
to investigate.
Thank you,
little white cabby.
♪♪
Oh, here comes
that boat again.
♪♪
♪ bee-oh ♪
Snipe.
Snipe, snipe.
Ahh.
Kolchak!
You out there?
Oh, haven't you people
done anything since I left?
Nothing.
What do you think
brought him out here?
Great selection, low prices.
Must have been
a good reason.
He had the counter with him.
Great place to die, though,
real spooky.
Captain, would you boys take
Logan's body back to the lab?
We'll join you there.
All right, doctor.
I'll go with you.
They can bring my car later.
Well, thank you, pinky.
Well, we'll just field strip him
and get out of here.
Do you have any idea of where
Logan was going this morning?
Well, when we got out
of bed there's a-- oh!
He said he was going into town
to pick up some personal things.
He was on a wifely errand.
I don't know of any special
plans he had.
Mentioned something
about "the horror."
If we can find out what brought
him to this particular place,
we might have
something to go on.
Good idea.
You know, we work good
together, Chris.
I'll just wait here then.
Rot, decompose.
Decompose.
Ah, poor sap.
Sky king!
It's Mathias rust.
Tonight on "wings,"
the beechcraft bonanza
with its revolutionary
"v" tail.
[Gasps]
[Coughing and sputtering]
Thank you, thing.
Hey, it's sununu,
going to get a haircut.
[Laughing]
'Cause he spent a lot of money
on planes.
Hot dog burp.
As far as the tragedies.
What do you mean?
Well, for the last eight weeks,
nothing has happened.
This is like
a totally other movie.
Whatever came back in that
capsule has disappeared.
You speak in riddles,
sahib.
And I thought this
was going to be a lockup.
I thought it
was just legwork
when Manning turned it over
to me.
- Legwork?
- Who are these guys?!
You know, detailed stuff.
Trivia.
There's nothing trivial
about three deaths.
That's for sure, and now I can
understand Chris's concern.
So let's get with it.
Well, where
do we start?
He looks like babe Ruth.
I'd like
to see Dr. Kramer.
Well, she's probably
in her lab.
Does she work alone?
Well, she started it
with Dr. Logan,
but now she works
with Conrad, his brother.
Well, let's go.
I'm glad
we had this talk.
I feel much closer
to you now.
Well, he's impotent.
And he's impotent, good.
I'm Chad,
from parke-Davis.
Dr. Brent,
Dr. Kramer.
Dr. Moe?
I'm glad to know you.
I filled Dr. Brent in
on the details,
but, well, let's get
to the larger issue.
Me.
Floor is yours, doctor.
Did you run a blood count
on Taylor?
Yes, we did.
Actually, there
was no blood.
It had all turned to powder,
and we think that accounts
for the shriveled effect.
Like shrinky dinks.
Well, how long was Taylor dead
before his body was found?
- It was just a matter of...
- Um, doctor, i--
doctor, if you could
look at this slide.
We think he was on his way
back to the copter...
Doctor, that full
polio vaccine, Dr. Salk?
Um, doctor, I think
I found it.
... it came back
to the capsule.
Doctor, if you just--
ohh.
It's true.
We have a radioactive
something or other.
- Thingy.
- Ten-foot tall, 400 pounds.
Well, that's a keeper.
Connors, if we sent
an astronaut up,
we got him back.
Dr. Salk, please, it's--
it's definitely
the polio vaccine.
Oh, forget it,
I'll take credit for it.
It's impossible.
With the perfect two-man
capsule, easy control...
Ooh, what a gesture!
Well, unless
I missed my guess,
Douglas is back.
A monster?
I don't know.
Apathetic scientists.
What about
this antedium 51
he was taking, the radiation
repellent?
Oh, yes, we actually gave him
lots more of these injections
so that he could withstand
all kinds of rays.
We've been working
on big gobs of neat stuff.
Well, did Dr. Logan
keep a log?
Certainly.
May I see it?
Yes.
Fine, jeez.
Weird, weird, weird.
Okay, let's see--
there's my journal,
this is my coin
collection book,
and then my book
of s&h green stamps.
This is Dr. Logan's log.
You'll find it very correct.
Well, let me see here.
Ahem!
Rumple tweezer, the good furry
lip, under the dum-dum tree?
What? Doh!
Regular Evelyn wood,
isn't he?
Do you keep a log?
Sure.
May I see it, please?
Yes, I'll get it.
Sure, I'll just
shelve my cancer research.
[Imitating rocky the squirrel]
"Bullwinkle is a"--
[imitating bullwinkle]
Not that lesson.
This lesson.
Ew, mayonnaise!
Sure is thorough.
That's why he's here.
He's thorough, yet gentle.
Why did you change
from antedium 50 to 51
six months ago?
Speaking of tedium...
Dr. Logan thought it would be
more effective.
The 50 was very effective.
It was tested on animals...
A two-year period,
the other for only six months.
I didn't know that.
Why wasn't I told?
Listen, I'm feeling
a little picked on here.
Dr. Logan was so sure
it would be all right.
Shame-based science.
Oh, another thing, doctor.
Dr. Logan states
this final injection
with Douglas is 100 ccs.
According to your log,
as compared to his,
yours says 200 ccs.
We keep two sets of books.
[Chuckles]
Who's correct, doctor?
I am only an assistant
in this laboratory.
I simply work here,
and I take my orders!
Dr. Brent didn't mean that.
Well, yes, I did,
actually.
Security must be upheld.
Where's Dr. Logan?
He's either in the commissary,
or perhaps he's back
in the other laboratory.
Well, let's go see him.
Perhaps we can
have drinks sometime, hmm?
Thank you.
Later, over lunch
with Wally Shawn.
I deal in facts.
I cross-checked
your logs with Dr. Kramer's.
That's proper.
You're head of the project.
Well, why wasn't I informed
about the switch
from antedium 50 to 51?
'Cause we hate you.
They're almost identical.
Well, then why not
call it 50-a?
I said almost identical.
Or heinz 57.
Antedium 51 can stand one-half
times more radiation.
You mean the subject
can stand more?
Precisely.
Hey, this ain't
rocket science, you know.
How did the animal experiments
work out?
- Perfectly.
- Fantastic.
For six months.
Well, what would happen
with, uh, overdose?
An overdose of anything,
candy with a child,
has a bad effect,
but is correctable.
Where's our pizza?
I just wanna go,
let's just go.
... with 200 ccs instead
of their customary 100 ccs?
Or was that
your brother's order?
- No.
- It was a joke!
Dr. Kramer is very efficient
and very observant.
I did give him an extra 100 ccs
for added protection.
That was my reason.
Did you ever overdose
an animal?
Well, I smoked
too much rabbit once.
It absorbed great quantities
of radiation.
The results, please.
The winner
in Los Angeles is...
... the other pigs.
So every one of them
it touched innocently.
Is that all?
No.
Whoever you are.
It grew twice
its normal size.
My brother developed
an antidote.
My brother's antidote can
beat your brother's antidote.
The animal died.
Of what, doctor?
The heart couldn't stand
the violent transition
back to normal.
And Douglas?
He's alive out there.
So another leinie?
Meanwhile, at lenscrafters...
Yeah, bad movies
in about an hour, right?
Working late, aren't you?
Don't you start on me,
baldy.
Oh, I just had
to finish this up.
I'm sorry, Mr. Gower,
please don't hit my sore ear!
Jeez, you break a beaker
over there or something?
Phew!
Isn't this fun
working on our own projects,
yet working together?
What do you think
of that Dr. Brent?
Ah, he's a pig.
Why?
He's a good man.
I don't know.
He really sort of scares me
with his exactness.
Makes you awfully aware
of your responsibility.
The hell?
He's got a job
to do.
I wouldn't want it.
Got any chlorofluorocarbons
over there?
Feels kind of
strange, though.
I mean, it's been so quiet
the past couple of weeks.
They're making
imposter fragrances.
Hmm.
Hope it stays that way.
Yeah.
No deaths,
no monster reports.
- [Sighs]
- Hmm.
I'm sorry,
you say something?
Oh.
I see you've made another batch
of antidote.
[Alarm rings]
[All] Ahh!
Pencils down.
It was your brother's
last order.
So, it was a good "Martin"
last night.
"What up?"
I love that part.
[Sniffing]
Good god, did you launch
a sulfur bomb back there, huh?
Whuh!
Hey, I figured it out!
He's got his script
taped to the floor.
[Sighs]
Well...
Let's play with phosphorus.
That does it.
Going home?
Look, I'm working late.
Aren't you?
Soon as I finish cleaning up
my desk.
This is what happens when you
get trapped in an ionesco play.
Mmm.
[Chuckles]
He's not mad at her anymore.
Yeah, looks like the experiment
was a success.
[Lecherous laugh]
I don't get it--
why is she changing lab coats?
She's got a night shift
at fermilab.
- Oh.
- Hmm?
Hmm?
Good night, doctor.
Oh, damn,
she loosened my script.
Hey! I think you got page 25
on your shoe!
Ahh... heh heh.
I'm gonna snoop
in her sock drawer.
[Chuckling]
Ah.
[Snoring loudly]
Dr. Logan did know
where the giant was.
In a storeroom in that
very building.
Logan had learned that
massive doses of the antidote
brought about an almost
human appearance.
I did not, quit lying!
... such unpredictable
side effects
that enough tranquilizer
to subdue ten ordinary men
had to be given each day.
On an empty stomach.
This day,
it was late.
Logan knew that each
passing minute
might mean
a return to violence.
♪ Return to violence ♪
As it turned out, he was
too late.
We was too late!
Like his brother,
the scientist
had an intuitive knowledge
of the situation,
plus an extraordinarily
bad sense of timing.
I feel like he laughs when bad
things happen to his friends.
Oh, that can
be embarrassing.
Look, the musical stairs
from the science museum.
♪♪
Wow, he's sneaking past
Robert fripp's room.
♪♪
[Hacks and spits]
Hit it!
♪♪
Hey, would somebody get the cat
off the Fender rhodes, please?
From there,
he looks like skitch Henderson.
♪ Ping ping ping ♪
[Whistles]
Oh, we don't need
to see this shot.
Agh.
♪♪ [Synthesizer music]
[All humming
"fly like an eagle"]
♪ Time keeps on slippin',
slippin...' ♪
♪ doo doo doo doo ♪
Ah, well, I guess
I didn't have to go.
[Electronic droning]
♪ Oh, what a lucky man
he was ♪
[All humming out-of-key]
I love hanging out
after school.
Nobody around.
Can go in the girls' room.
Heh heh.
Everything used
to make the antidote
was in wreckage by the time
Logan returned.
That's wreckage?
Any chance that might
have existed,
any hope that sufficient
antidote might be compounded
to have a lasting effect,
all this vanished with one sweep
of the monster's arm.
Or any hope that
the film would end soon.
Oh, man, he got
my "compuserve" magazine
and "computer gamer weekly"!
It might have been nice
to show that scene
with the monster,
but use your imagination.
It was true horror.
Oh, man,
I need a smoke.
I'm dying for a cigarette.
I really need a smoke.
Oh--
hello?
If you'd like
to make a call...
Get to laboratory d.
- If you'd like to make a...
- Hurry.
Are you listen--
I said, if you'd like to make--
- this is Dr. Logan.
- Listen to me.
- If you'd like to make a--
- is Dr. Brent there?
- Ah, for-- can it.
- Put him on.
Oh, great, I'm dead.
It's the end of the world.
- I'm dead.
- Dr. Brent.
I'll be right over.
Yes... it's urgent.
The call is coming
from within the laboratory!
Great, I'm dead.
I'm a dead man--
a dead man and walking
and talking in my clothes.
That's how dead I am--
I'm dead.
- I'm dead.
- What a day.
I invented gaines-burgers,
and I didn't even mean to!
Ah, here to borrow
more test tubes?
Can't keep your own stock up?
What do you mean
was here?
I hid him in my radiation lab
for weeks.
I've been giving him
an injection of antidote.
- That was dumb, jer.
- Mm-hmm.
Why weren't we informed?
Blame it on my state
of shock or--
blame it on the bossa nova.
I could only think
to help him first.
Kiss that nobel good-bye.
Did the antidote
do any good?
Yes, he became normal.
Except for size.
He was huge, but normal.
Why weren't
we informed then?
I could only think of logging
what I'd witnessed.
All right,
so you logged it.
Why didn't you
tell us then?
I don't know.
I was trying to help.
I was just trying to help.
Help?
You've jeopardized
this whole project.
What the hell do you
want from me, Dr. Brent?
I don't have a precision mind
like yours.
- I'm only a scientist!
- Fine, I made a mistake.
But the fact is, frank Douglas
is gone with the antidote.
Hey, you came
into my l ab, you know?
You're the jerk.
Huzzah!
Go ahead, spank me.
Chalk me up
as incompetent.
Well...
It's all right.
We can laugh about it now,
buddy.
We're both a little bit edgy.
I was just thinking
one mistake can be...
[Laughing]
Boy, I can't stay mad at you.
We better call...
It's the group.
- Oh.
- [Humming]
I'm in love, Jim!
[Birds tweeting]
This is like "vanity fair"
by Sam peckinpah.
Hmm.
Whoa, that guy's
got a weird shape.
- No, crow, it's a--
- oh.
Now, that's science.
- Oh.
- Connect the dots.
Science!
Duh, hello, ladies,
which way to the beach?
Jeez, he's kind of
a lumpy fella.
Hmm, in all the wrong places.
[Pinging]
Duracell,
the copper top battery.
Hi, I'm from the boy's camp
across the lake.
A backup generator exploded.
[Pinging continues]
Is it the bangles?
The go-go's?
The lark quartet?
Well...
- [All screaming]
- The Beatles!
The is the "a-go go" part
here.
No one's going
to tell you need clearasil.
Damn, damn, stupid, stupid,
what was I thinking?
Oh, damn...
Hey, a whole bottle
of sea & ski!
- Unbelievable.
- [Laughing]
General Connors?
Yes?
I made that phone noise.
Where?
They panicked.
Are you saying
it was my fault?
Was anyone seriously hurt?
No, thank god.
Well, he's got to be stopped
before anything else happens.
- Washington called.
- He did?
They put me
completely in charge.
Now, they want results,
and they want 'em fast.
I need to know some answers.
Please phrase it
in the form of a question.
Is there anything else
I should know?
- Are your flies open?
- I'm doing all I can.
It's not enough.
I don't need you
busting my butt.
They want answers,
they want 'em now.
Now, don't mince words.
All right, but understand,
this is just a theory.
But I'm coco Chanel!
Douglas
is much worse.
And?
And if my theory is correct,
he gets
progressively worse.
Quit kidding a kidder.
What do you mean?
Well, when I first hid him
in the other lab,
I gave him an injection
of the antidote
my brother
and Nora developed.
John Lilly called
for the prescription.
It worked, and he
became almost normal.
But the condition
lasted only five days.
- Then...
- He left for the weekend.
... with each following
injection,
the effect of the antidote
wore off more rapidly.
What are you trying to say?
I'm coco Chanel!
The last injection was effective
for only a few hours.
Are you trying
to tell me--
- precisely.
- There's your punch.
It means, colonel, that
if he is using the antidote
he escaped with
as his body needs it...
Hmm.
There is no telling
how bad he will get
after each
injection wears off.
- Good read.
- That's a wrap.
No, he doesn't get larger.
The radius
of his danger zone does.
Isn't that always the way,
though?
Perhaps he doesn't
have any antidote.
I'm not sure,
but it's conceivable...
Inconceivable!
That within hours,
he could contaminate
everything and everybody
within a radius of 50 miles.
That settles it.
- Uhh, sausage burp.
- He has got to be destroyed.
Alert the entire division.
Civilian forces,
anything else that's available.
He's got to be kept out
of populated areas.
Or it'll be bonkers.
I want you with me
every minute.
[Giggling]
Yes, sir, thank you, sir.
[All]
♪ John Jacob
jingleheimer schmidt ♪
♪ that's my name too ♪
♪ whenever I go out,
the people always shout ♪
♪ there goes John Jacob
jingleheimer schmidt ♪
♪ la-la-la-la-la-la-la ♪
[Laughing]
Oh, that was fun.
Ah, thanks, Kyle.
As the giant became bolder,
his whereabouts
were more easily tracked,
and the army was called out
in force.
Because this was,
after all,
an American astronaut...
Oh, right.
Official orders
were not to fire.
But one nervous soldier
is all that is ever needed
to start a panic.
Oh, blame it
on the little guy!
You're going in the house,
Joseph.
Let me go!
My gosh, look!
Hmm?
[Gunshots]
- Uh, lower, aim a little lower!
- Yeah.
♪ Whenever I go out ♪
♪ the people always shout ♪
♪ there goes John Jacob
jingleheimer schmidt ♪
♪ la-da-da-da-da-da ♪
[All laughing]
So the army's on maneuvers
on maple street, huh?
And in econoline vans.
Ah, acceptable losses,
everybody, come on.
[Indistinct shouting]
Hey, they're gonna
fry the director.
Good.
I'm guessing
this is a night scene?
Huh?
- Oh.
- [Muttering]
Ah, good.
Yeah, let's see if we can--
oh, wait.
Oh, wait.
- Oh.
- Ohh.
[Gunshot]
Huh, something's going on.
That comes to 12.90.
You want any pop with that?
Hello?
Uh, he-hello?
Johnny Carson!
Douglas was at the house.
Your mother's
very upset.
It was like shooting
at a wall.
Not a very big wall.
"The lean."
Now what, doctor?
Well, first,
let me finish my Toledo.
I...
I don't know.
What are they doing
at a laundromat?
Well, he can't get very far.
The map isn't that big.
[Laughs]
We have the entire area
surrounded.
We'll have him
within an hour.
Yes.
But then what?
[Engine stalling]
Jackie o?
- Ohh...
- Ooh.
[Engine stalling]
Hmm?
Boy, smooth ride.
Hardly looks
like she's moving.
Ah-- oh, she's not.
Hmm...
Must be the car.
Well, the door still works.
That's good.
Oh, this is like
"it happened one night,"
except it makes me
want to kill myself.
[All muttering]
Luckily,
the schwan's guy came.
You wanna get killed
or something?
My car broke down!
Well, then, call
the automobile club.
Oh, hey, I thought truck drivers
were the gentlemen of the road.
Where'd you hear that crap?
Yeah, well,
let's see, lady.
Maybe we can save a lot of time
here, let's see.
Puh! Ding!
Well, I see the front
torpedo bays are loaded.
Can't be your generator.
How'd it stop like?
Well, I don't know
what you mean.
Well, I mean, did it
stop and start?
Tom Arnold's
road repair.
- No, it was sputtering.
- Oh, sputtering.
Oh, yeah, lady.
Oh, hey,
where are you going?
I'm gonna get you
some gas.
Oh, is that all?
It's funny, you see,
'cause women don't know
anything about cars.
That's so humor.
Ah, we just keep an open can
of gas behind the seat.
He's putting
ginseng tea in her car.
Big tea kettle.
Lady, could you move, uh,
your, uh...
I'm gonna watch closely so I can
do this myself next time.
Lady, would you mind
going and sitting in the car?
You're making me nervous.
Yes, sir.
Dear "easy rider" magazine,
I never believed
your stories were true!
- [Laughs] Ptt!
- Hmm.
Well, she's facing
the wrong way.
No wonder
the car's not working.
Ohh.
Well, now.
Open up your hood.
Oh, you'd like that,
wouldn't you?
Uh, can I check the windows
for you?
[Chortling]
Heck, there's a thing wrong
with your whatchamacallit here.
[Pinging]
Hmm?
Huh?
There we go.
Move over, lady,
I'll start it for you.
'Cause women known nothing
about cars.
Now, see, it's funny.
Yeah.
[Engine starts]
What'd he do,
light the pilot?
Ah.
[Revving engine]
Hey there, ma'am,
for god's sake, next time
drive on a full tank of gas.
Thank you, Lancelot.
Kelly's the name,
ma'am-- Kelly.
Show him the can, Andy.
What's this for?
My way of appreciation.
Thanks would have been enough,
lady.
Now you wrecked it.
Driver?
I need love.
Hmm?
Ma'am?
- Oh, uck!
- Eww.
- Yuck.
- Whoa.
She stalls, then kills:
Black widow.
Oh, wow, what a smoothie.
Lancelot.
Third time today, heh heh.
New hairstyle's
really working.
Ptt! Ding!
[Creaking and whooshing]
Okay, change
furnace filters, done.
Jettison dry-cleaning,
check.
- Okay, young fresh fellows.
- Huh?
I've got the rest of
the afternoon off to talk about
some of the questions
of the universe,
so any question
you might have, ask me.
You have
my undivided attention.
Oh, no, we meant
to prepare for this.
Please, crow, let's don't
make it like last week
when you asked what was the deal
with Jane pauley's hair, okay?
- I just--
- I had this idea.
Okay, not Jane pau--
okay.
[Whispering]
Well, then you do it.
You--
okay, you do it.
Yeah, you--
do what you said.
- Joel?
- Yeah?
- "The pina colada song."
- Yeah!
Uh, could you phrase it
in the form of a question?
Okay, Joel, what's the deal
with the pina colada song?
Oh, and I have a follow-up.
Okay, you mean, "if you like
pina coladas,
"getting caught in the rain,
"if you're not into health food
and you have half a brain,
if you like making love
at midnight on the dunes--"
- that's the one.
- Yep, yep, yep.
Well, okay, um...
All right,
in the early 1980s,
Rupert Holmes wrote
"the pina colada song"
because pina coladas
and personal ads
were on the forefront
of the American consciousness,
and you know, pop song writers
do just that.
They write about pop culture,
you know,
like, you know, there's
ray Stevens' "the streak,"
Henry gross's
"junk food junkie,"
c.w. McCall's "convoy,"
and others.
- Oh.
- Not so fast there, neon peon.
Okay, so this man and woman
are in this relationship for,
oh, let's say
eight months.
That's the average national
length of a dating relationship
of males 18-34.
And they don't even know that
each other likes pina coladas?
What, would
they always panic
and order Manhattans
or something?
Yeah, and wouldn't
they probably already have
been caught in the rain
together,
and then one of them
at least mentioned
that they liked
getting caught in the rain?
Mm-hmm,
and if this couple--
well, we'll call them
Rick and Julie
for the purposes
of this argument--
if Julie and Rick had been
together for any amount of time,
well, doesn't each of them
have a responsibility
to communicate to the other
his or her dissatisfaction
with the relationship?
Yeah, 'cause by responding
to the personals ads,
not only are they
cheating on each other,
they're cheating on each other
with each other.
Yeah, and since 72% of
the population of North America
lives in a landlocked state
or province,
in actuality,
this couple has no idea
whether they like making love
on the dunes in the cape.
And it's probably
one-in-a-kazillion chance
that Rick and Julie
would actually
answer each other's ads!
Bingo! And although the song
tries to paint a rosy picture
of a relationship reborn,
it is human nature
that either Rick or Julie,
maybe both, I don't know,
would harbor at least
a fragment of resentment
that the other set out
to cheat on him or her,
which would
unleash itself in fits
of passive-aggressive behavior
and bitter recrimination.
Okay, listen.
All I'm saying is that
Rupert Holmes
wrote a song about a couple
of popular trends, all right?
It doesn't make the hurt
go away.
We don't blame you, Joel.
Hey, Rupert Holmes
wrote "Timothy."
That was about cannibalism.
When was that popular?
Listen, crow, it's a well-known
fact that Timothy was a duck.
Wait a minute,
let's review here.
- A duck?
- Caught in a coal mine.
Get "hungry as hell..."
Gee, that leg
looks swell, um...
- Doc.
- My word.
In the city?
Yes, sir, he got there on
a truck.
The driver suffered
radiation burns.
How the hell are we going
to find him now?
"Beetle Bailey:
The motion picture."
Do you realize there's over five
million people in the city?
And this is one of them.
The danger zone should be
20 to 25 feet.
Nora...
How long would it take to mix up
3,000 ccs of the antidote?
Not too long.
But I'd need a blender.
Do it.
And get it to me,
immediately.
Okay.
But you won't like it.
We'll need an air gun
and a tranquilizer dart.
A string and a picture
of Eve arden!
Whoo!
We'll track him down
with geiger counters.
That means we'll have
to get within 20 or 25 feet.
It means you'll have to get off
your butts and do something!
He takes one step,
and we're in the danger zone.
Hey, a new angle.
Wait a minute...
There may be another way.
Nah, forget it,
we don't have another room.
If we placed counters
in strategic locations,
surrounding the entire area
where the truck driver's body
was found,
we could then connect
the counters
to a centralized oscilloscope.
You know, you look good
without your glasses.
It would give us
his exact position
without endangering
any more lives.
Hmm, hmm.
You like jell-o with fruit
suspended in it?
It could work.
Let's try it.
[All]
Nah!
What would be his radius
of danger within an hour?
Reykjavik.
Oh, about 100 feet
or more.
Huh, 100.
Oh, that's nice.
Hmm, sure,
mm-hmm.
It's hard to say.
Let me say it in a song.
Wait.
Mm, I...
Dear diary, the general
yelled at me today.
Oh, out of time.
Gotta go, more later.
Love, bunny.
I can't go on
like this.
Your blood tests came back.
If you're thinking of shooting
that antidote into him
at this range,
you'd better
make the first shot count.
Come on, perk up, bill.
I'm fully aware
of the consequences.
Slower!
Oh, slower!
♪♪ [Imitating military drums]
The caisson is making its way
past us now.
The riderless horse float
is made of 10,000 carnations,
and clowns are pouring out
of the casket.
Lovely sight.
♪♪ [Trilling military march]
- Hmm?
- Hey, it's the good humor cop!
Mmm, dreamsicles.
I'm up, I'm up!
Hmm, so...
So... oh!
Here comes roasty and toasty,
the firemen clowns!
- Ha ha!
- Guh, guh!
They're ice fishing!
[Goofy laughter]
You know, these cable guys
always come
when it's least convenient.
[Snickering]
It's a joke.
Abbott and costello
in "buck privates."
We're getting cable
'cause this movie's so bad.
[Laughter]
[All shrieking]
A city of five million people
became a huge tomb.
Like St. Paul?
The civil defense unit
swung into action.
The festive jitneys
ran down the streets of Manila.
[Truck engine shuts off]
Uh, exact change only.
City streets were cleared
of all but official personnel.
With the realization that
even seeing the monster
might mean that
an individual was close enough
to absorb a lethal dose
of radioactivity.
How you doing, Steve?
- Oh, not bad, how 'bout you?
- Ah, pretty good.
But right now,
we'll join the auto show
at mccormick place.
The long wait began.
And you're gonna see
every minute of it.
[Shudders]
Isaac Hayes is truck Turner.
[Beatboxing]
[Brakes squeak]
Uh, thanks, mom,
we'll walk from here.
Now I'll be back to pick you up
after fireman practice.
- Whatever.
- Okay.
- ♪ Hello ♪
- ♪ hello ♪
[All]
Hello!
[Sirens approaching]
Watch out for
the first draft.
[Chuckles]
Uh, bad news,
you're not in this scene.
So... why'd you bring
the leaf blower, Walt?
Hello?
Hello, anything going on?
Uh, eh-- hello?
H-Hello?
Hiya, hi.
Darkness on the edge of town.
Cute.
Hey, "outer limits"
is startin'!
Hey, that guy's
got an action torso.
Mm.
Boy, you know, it sure doesn't
feel like a Tuesday.
Yeah, yeah,
it's Dave's birthday.
We're passing the card.
Let me finish here.
Uh... year older.
[Chuckling]
Huh?
Oh, looks like the monster
rented a loft apartment.
Oh.
[Pinging]
Listen.
Billy pilgrim has become
unstuck in time.
It's his 12-step program.
- Ohh.
- 'Cause it's steps and...
Mm-hmm.
Ladies and gentlemen, kmoj radio
presents bootsy Collins!
Look,
he's got gout, poor guy.
What are we supposed to do
if something happens?
Just stand here?
Nah, take your lunch break.
Shut up
and watch the scope.
Look! Look, we're getting
something!
- What, what?
- It's "major dad."
- What's the location?
- Ah!
It's only
a few blocks from here!
Better make that call now.
[Pinging]
- Will you cut that out?
- They're on their way.
Look-- look,
it's going crazy.
[Horn honking, siren wailing]
They finally realized
that the monster had tickets
to see loggins and messina
at the arie crown theater.
Oh, they're stopping
at the Billy goat
for a cheezeborger.
And coke?
[Both]
No, Pepsi.
Ah.
If I didn't know better,
I'd think this
were a security camera.
All right, $3, special event
parking.
Okay, back, back.
That's fine, back a little.
[Imitates crashing sound]
That's perfect.
Laszlo kovacs,
my butt!
This is great photography!
Huh, still early.
Probably a lot of people
coming after church.
Yep.
[All]
♪ there goes John Jacob
jingleheimer schmidt ♪
- [All laughing]
- All right.
Hey, this is so weird,
you're here, too.
We're going to Wayne's after
this-- are you on?
Whoo, we're on!
They freakin' ripped off
the French connection
train sequence
from this movie!
You know, four movies went
into the making of this film.
- Huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, where is it?
Who's winning?
One block north
and then two blocks west.
Sir, I'm losing him.
Maybe you should have been
more sensitive to his needs!
I've lost him,
I can't get him anywhere!
Well, remember why you
got together with him
in the first place.
I have a geiger counter
right here.
[Pinging]
Mmm, cookie!
- Mmm...
- [Munching sounds]
Could he have
destroyed the counter?
Anyone know how to read
this thing?
Give me a counter.
We decided we need the help of
a housewife and a balding guy.
Would you rather go?
Ahh, go clean
your laboratory.
Jeez, flippin' scientists
wrecked our thing.
Yep, my kind
of town, Chicago is.
You bet.
Now, Chicago's
the windy city, right?
Ah, it's the city
by the lake,
or city of big shoulders,
or city that works?
Are you scared, sarge?
Well, of course
I'm scared.
Anyone who isn't scared
is either a coward or a liar.
Yeah, every time I aim
a wham-o air blaster
at a sidewalk,
I get scared.
Yeah?
What about now?
Yeah, I'm scared, I'm scared.
Okay.
Well, our research is over--
it's pavement.
Time to go home.
Laverne and Shirley
in the national guard.
[Indistinct chatter]
Sarge!
Ever worry that you
don't have a face?
Really doesn't
go anywhere, sir.
No sense of why.
These tracks.
"These pants"?
Is there any other way in?
To your pants?
Uh, the north entrance
is blocked from the outside.
Man, if you can't out-act
a post...
[Laughs]
[Humming]
The bookmobile is called in.
Oh, I hope they still have
"curious George."
Oh, yeah, yeah.
- Riff.
- Mm!
Oh, here you go, you'll lose
ten pounds in this suit.
Ow!
Ow, watch that!
My crack, ouch!
Okay, major, do you dress
to the right or to the left?
Oh, wait, don't say no
right away.
Oh, that's some nice...
Here, let's build that up and
see what the final look will be.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
[Squeaking]
Oh, oh, pull the helmet off!
[Muffled]
Get it off me!
This is the most dramatic
asbestos suit scene
I've ever seen.
- Yep.
- Oh, that tickles!
Don't touch the armpits.
Okay, now put your arms
together in front.
Pull your pants up a bit.
There you go.
Wow, dual overhead dressers.
- Oh.
- Mm-hmm.
Jeez, is there anything else
I have to put on?
My brother and I look like
wood ticks ready to pop.
♪♪
[All]
♪ eee-oh... ♪
♪ Eee-oh... ♪
I-- I know.
Ah, get me, I'm a Stewart
sandwich with a rifle, agh.
[Snorts]
Right, ahem, don't laugh.
Here they come.
Be cool.
[Snorts]
- Don't say it.
- Wasn't my idea.
There is one terrifying word
in the world of nuclear physics.
- "Oops."
- radiation.
- Oh.
As the trail grew hot, so did
the level of contamination.
Here was a problem
the civil defense authorities
had never before faced
and might never see again.
How to end this film.
Special equipment
never tested
under actual emergency
conditions was brought in.
A killer.
The mouth of the sewer tunnel
became the center of action.
Oh, I'm outta here.
[Train whistle blowing]
♪ There's a little hotel
called the shady rest ♪
♪ at the junction ♪
[Scatting]
Sorry, we should have had this
cleaned before you got here.
[Chuckles]
Well...
Well, it's not like
I'm tasting my own sweat
in this suit--
would you hurry up?
[Whispering]
For sure.
Well, would you look?
All the canned peaches
you could want!
... radiation is
a decontamination spray,
which reduces the level
of radiation...
Benedictus qui venit
in nomine domini.
Amen.
... that were all that man could
use against forces
too large for him to comprehend.
Tune in tomorrow.
In the director's cut,
they eliminated the narration.
- Oh.
- Hmm.
♪♪
♪ eee-oh ♪
Come on, dummy.
If we don't find grandma,
can we come up?
Uh, you think I should
tell him his zipper's down?
Ah.
[Pinging]
♪ Nightmare the clown ♪
♪ he's coming to your town,
hey ♪
[Goofy laughter
and grunting]
Ooh.
Time for your medication,
Mr. Taylor.
No, she's not one
of the Germans, Mr. Taylor.
[Pinging]
So I said to the kid, "either
get a job or get a haircut."
No kid's gonna live in my house
like that.
- Nah, I know what you mean.
- Ahh.
What are you gonna do?
So, lunch?
- Ah, okay.
- Yeah.
[Pinging continues]
It's "American gothic"
on a rampage.
He's not bad,
he's just misunderstood.
So what do you want to do
when we're done?
Oh, let's go to ginos.
Hey, how hot
is your suit, Bob?
I'm sweating bbs.
- Mm.
As if a switch
had been turned,
as if an eye had
been blinked,
as if some phantom force
in the universe
had made a move
eons beyond our comprehension...
As if we cared.
... suddenly,
there was no trail.
There was no giant,
no monster,
no thing
called Douglas to be followed.
There was nothing
in the tunnel
but the puzzled
men of courage
who suddenly found themselves
alone with shadows and darkness.
There was no dignity for anyone
who worked on this film!
Huh, well,
this was a bust.
Let's get out of here.
Come on, let's call the movie
on account of darkness.
That's a wrap, everyone!
Strike the set.
Turned out to be an alien
snipe hunt, go figure.
This was a test.
Had this been
an actual movie,
you would have been
entertained.
Phil silvers
tries to flee the set.
Um, uh, this is a note
from the director.
"Thank you, everybody,
the film is over."
Not everybody
will get paid tonight.
You'll have
to check the sheet, okay?
What the...
It says, "sell the house,
sell the car, sell the kids.
I'm never coming back"?
... and another descends.
Astronaut frank Douglas
rescued,
alive, well,
and of normal size
some 8,000 miles away
in a lifeboat.
- Oh, come on!
- Wait a minute!
Lame.
... or how he was separated
from his capsule.
Then who
or what has landed here?
I thought we covered that.
Is it here yet, or has
the cosmic switch been pulled?
You make the call!
Case in point:
The line between
science fiction
- and science fact...
- And science crap.
... is microscopically thin.
You have witnessed the line
being shaved even thinner.
- Mm-hmm.
- Golly, the joke's on us.
- But is the menace with us?
- Boo!
- Or is the monster gone?
- Ohh.
Boo!
- Whoa!
- Boo!
- Terrible.
[Overlapping chatter]
Oh, I've got an idea
to cheer us up.
[Whooshing and creaking]
Okay, I knew this movie might
get you down, Tom, so voila!
You're a happy king!
♪♪ [Imitating fanfare]
Great little song there, Joel,
real dignified.
Think I'll go
throw myself out an airlock.
Oh, come back here, Tom,
come on.
Every-- you know,
every kid on earth
dreams of becoming
a happy king.
♪♪ [Imitating trumpet fanfare]
Yeah, fine,
Joel, whatever.
I just rolled off
the turnip truck.
And, crow t. Robot,
by the power vested in me
by the kingdom of cookieville,
I now pronounce you
sir giggles Von laughs-a-lot.
Joel, I beg you not pronounce me
Your job, sir giggles,
is to make sure that king Tom
remains a happy
and cheerful king.
♪♪ [Imitating trumpet fanfare]
- [Sobbing]
- Hey, what--
what's wrong?
Joel, it's this movie.
It was really
depressing.
It was like--
it was like being a little kid
and eating dinner at your aunt
Ruth's apartment in the suburbs,
and it's hot in there,
and she's got a local
Christian radio station on,
and there's nothing to do
or look at
'cause all she's
got in the apartment
are "good housekeeping"
magazines and linen doilies.
Yeah, and then
they send you out
to play with the strange
neighbor kids,
and they're all big,
and their skin is pink,
and they have big pores,
and the big eighth-grader
makes you look
at really upsetting pictures.
And so you go back inside
and sit down,
and they're
all just talking,
and there are big pauses
in their conversation.
And you can hear the clock
ticking on the wall!
Yeah, yeah, and so you
dig into your seat cushion,
and you find
a really old peanut,
and you're so bored,
you eat it.
And then you just feel bad
and a little sick and--
and then you think
you're about to go, but then--
then aunt Ruth
takes out a photo album
filled with black and white
photos of kids with squinty eyes
and they're supposed to be your
uncle and aunts or something.
And then your parents force you
to look at them!
Okay, okay,
come on, come on.
We're tougher than that,
you guys, come on.
Let's think of
something good about the movie.
Come on, sir mix-a-lot.
It's sir giggles
Von laughs-a-lot.
I mean, sir giggles Von
laughs-a-lot.
Um... oh...
- Come on.
- Uh... what?
Uh, oh, you couldn't hear
the dialogue.
Oh, right,
now that's a good one.
What about you,
king Tom?
Uh, okay, okay,
don't tell me.
No one involved
with this dung heap went--
never went on
to do anything else!
Right, all right,
that's a good thing.
You see, sirs, you can
throw us any crummy movie
you've got--
we can take it.
Or my name's not
Joel Robinson.
Yeah, my name's not Tom
"happy king" Servo!
Yeah, and my name
is not...
Crow t. Sir giggles
Von laughs-a-robot-whatever.
Yeah, and i'm
not even gypsy!
[All]
Yeah!
What do you think, sirs?
Yeah.
- [Blows raspberry]
- Ha!
Yeah.
That's fine, Joel.
Have your petty little
insurrection.
Just remember,
you're trapped in space,
dressed like happy kings,
and frank and I
are down here on earth,
free to do whatever we want.
Hey, Dr. F., there's a "Matlock"
marathon on tonight.
- You in?
- Oh!
Push the button, frank.